{
  "N5L1VQuiz": [
    { "question": "I", "kanji_question": "私", "answer": "わたし" },
    { "question": "you", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あなた" },
    { "question": "that person, he, she", "kanji_question": "あの人", "answer": "あのひと" },
    { "question": "polite equivalent of あのひと", "kanji_question": "あの方", "answer": "あのかた" },
    { "question": "Mr., Ms. ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～さん" },
    { "question": "~ suffix to child", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ちゃん" },
    { "question": "a national of ~", "kanji_question": "～人", "answer": "～じん" },
    { "question": "teacher, instructor (other people)", "kanji_question": "先生", "answer": "せんせい" },
    { "question": "teacher, instructor (self)", "kanji_question": "教師", "answer": "きょうし" },
    { "question": "student", "kanji_question": "学生", "answer": "がくせい" },
    { "question": "company employee", "kanji_question": "会社員", "answer": "かいしゃいん" },
    { "question": "employee of ~", "kanji_question": "～社員", "answer": "～しゃいん" },
    { "question": "bank employee", "kanji_question": "銀行員", "answer": "ぎんこういん" },
    { "question": "medical doctor", "kanji_question": "医者", "answer": "いしゃ" },
    { "question": "researcher, scholar", "kanji_question": "研究者", "answer": "けんきゅうしゃ" },
    { "question": "university", "kanji_question": "大学", "answer": "だいがく" },
    { "question": "hospital", "kanji_question": "病院", "answer": "びょういん" },
    { "question": "who", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だれ" },
    { "question": "polite equivalent of だれ", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どなた" },
    { "question": "~ years old", "kanji_question": "～歳", "answer": "～さい" },
    { "question": "how old", "kanji_question": "何歳", "answer": "なんさい" },
    { "question": "polite equivalent of なんさい", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おいくつ" },
    { "question": "yes", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はい" },
    { "question": "no", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいえ" },
    { "question": "How do you do?", "kanji_question": "初めまして。", "answer": "はじめまして。" },
    { "question": "I came from ~.", "kanji_question": "～から来ました。", "answer": "～からきました。" },
    { "question": "Pleased to meet you.", "kanji_question": "「どうぞ」よろしく「お願いします」。", "answer": "「どうぞ」よろしく「おねがいします」。" },
    { "question": "Excuse me, but", "kanji_question": "失礼ですが", "answer": "しつれいですが" },
    { "question": "May I have your name?", "kanji_question": "お名前は？", "answer": "おなまえは？" },
    { "question": "This is Mr./Ms.~.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こちらは～さんです。" },
    { "question": "U.S.A.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アメリカ" },
    { "question": "U.K.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "イギリス" },
    { "question": "India", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "インド" },
    { "question": "Indonesia", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "インドネシア" },
    { "question": "South Korea", "kanji_question": "韓国", "answer": "かんこく" },
    { "question": "Thailand", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "タイ" },
    { "question": "China", "kanji_question": "中国", "answer": "ちゅうごく" },
    { "question": "Germany", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ドイツ" },
    { "question": "Japan", "kanji_question": "日本", "answer": "にほん" },
    { "question": "Brazil", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ブラジル" }
  ],
  "N5L2VQuiz": [
    { "question": "this (thing here)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これ" },
    { "question": "that (things near you)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それ" },
    { "question": "that (things over there)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あれ" },
    { "question": "this ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "この～" },
    { "question": "that ~ (near you)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "その～" },
    { "question": "that ~ (over there)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あの～" },
    { "question": "book", "kanji_question": "本", "answer": "ほん" },
    { "question": "dictionary", "kanji_question": "辞書", "answer": "じしょ" },
    { "question": "magazine", "kanji_question": "雑誌", "answer": "ざっし" },
    { "question": "newspaper", "kanji_question": "新聞", "answer": "しんぶん" },
    { "question": "notebook", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ノート" },
    { "question": "pocket notebook", "kanji_question": "手帳", "answer": "てちょう" },
    { "question": "business card", "kanji_question": "名刺", "answer": "めいし" },
    { "question": "card", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カード" },
    { "question": "pencil", "kanji_question": "鉛筆", "answer": "えんぴつ" },
    { "question": "ballpoint pen", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ボールペン" },
    { "question": "mechanical pencil, propelling pencil", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シャープペンシル" },
    { "question": "key", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かぎ" },
    { "question": "watch, clock", "kanji_question": "時計", "answer": "とけい" },
    { "question": "umbrella", "kanji_question": "傘", "answer": "かさ" },
    { "question": "bag, briefcase", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かばん" },
    { "question": "CD, compact disc", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "CD" },
    { "question": "television", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "テレビ" },
    { "question": "radio", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ラジオ" },
    { "question": "camera", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カメラ" },
    { "question": "computer", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コンピューター" },
    { "question": "car, vehicle", "kanji_question": "車", "answer": "くるま" },
    { "question": "desk", "kanji_question": "机", "answer": "つくえ" },
    { "question": "chair", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いす" },
    { "question": "chocolate", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "チョコレート" },
    { "question": "coffee", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コーヒー" },
    { "question": "souvenir, present", "kanji_question": "「お」土産", "answer": "「お」みやげ" },
    { "question": "English", "kanji_question": "英語", "answer": "えいご" },
    { "question": "Japanese", "kanji_question": "日本語", "answer": "にほんご" },
    { "question": "~ language", "kanji_question": "～語", "answer": "～ご" },
    { "question": "what", "kanji_question": "何", "answer": "なん" },
    { "question": "so", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そう" },
    { "question": "well (hesitation)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あのう" },
    { "question": "Oh? What! (used when hearing something unexpected)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "えっ" },
    { "question": "Please. Here you are.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうぞ。" },
    { "question": "Thank you [very much].", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「どうも」ありがとう「ございます」。" },
    { "question": "I see.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そうですか。" },
    { "question": "No, it isn't./You are wrong.", "kanji_question": "違います。", "answer": "ちがいます。" },
    { "question": "Oh! (used when becoming aware of something)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あ、" },
    { "question": "I hope for your kind assistance hereafter.", "kanji_question": "これからお世話になります。", "answer": "これからおせわになります。"},
    { "question": "Pleased to meet you, too. (response to「どうぞ」よろしく「おねがいします」。)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こちらこそ「どうぞ」よろしく「おねがいします」。" }
  ],
  "N5L3VQuiz": [
    { "question": "here, this place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ここ" },
    { "question": "there, that place near you", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そこ" },
    { "question": "over there, that place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あそこ" },
    { "question": "where, what place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どこ" },
    { "question": "this way, this place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こちら" },
    { "question": "that way, that place near you", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そちら" },
    { "question": "that way, that place over there", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あちら" },
    { "question": "which way, where", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どちら" },
    { "question": "classroom", "kanji_question": "教室", "answer": "きょうしつ" },
    { "question": "dining hall, canteen", "kanji_question": "食堂", "answer": "しょくどう" },
    { "question": "office", "kanji_question": "事務所", "answer": "じむしょ" },
    { "question": "conference room, assembly room", "kanji_question": "会議室", "answer": "かいぎしつ" },
    { "question": "reception desk", "kanji_question": "受付", "answer": "うけつけ" },
    { "question": "lobby", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ロビー" },
    { "question": "room", "kanji_question": "部屋", "answer": "へや" },
    { "question": "toilet, rest room (informal)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "トイレ" },
    { "question": "toilet, rest room (formal)", "kanji_question": "お手洗い", "answer": "おてあらい" },
    { "question": "staircase", "kanji_question": "階段", "answer": "かいだん" },
    { "question": "elevator, lift", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "エレベーター" },
    { "question": "escalator", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "エスカレーター" },
    { "question": "vending machine", "kanji_question": "自動販売機", "answer": "じどうはんばいき" },
    { "question": "telephone handset, telephone call", "kanji_question": "電話", "answer": "でんわ" },
    { "question": "country", "kanji_question": "「お」国", "answer": "「お」くに" },
    { "question": "company", "kanji_question": "会社", "answer": "かいしゃ" },
    { "question": "house, home", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うち" },
    { "question": "shoes", "kanji_question": "靴", "answer": "くつ" },
    { "question": "necktie", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ネクタイ" },
    { "question": "wine", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ワイン" },
    { "question": "department, counter (in a department store)", "kanji_question": "売り場", "answer": "うりば" },
    { "question": "basement", "kanji_question": "地下", "answer": "ちか" },
    { "question": "~th floor", "kanji_question": "～階", "answer": "～かい" },
    { "question": "what floor", "kanji_question": "何階", "answer": "なんがい" },
    { "question": "~yen", "kanji_question": "～円", "answer": "～えん" },
    { "question": "how much", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いくら" },
    { "question": "hundred", "kanji_question": "百", "answer": "ひゃく" },
    { "question": "thousand", "kanji_question": "千", "answer": "せん" },
    { "question": "ten thousand", "kanji_question": "万", "answer": "まん" },
    { "question": "Excuse me.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すみません。" },
    { "question": "Thanks.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうも。" },
    { "question": "Welcome./May I help you? (a greeting to a customer or guest entering a shop, etc.)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いらっしゃいませ。" },
    { "question": "Please show me ~.", "kanji_question": "～を見せてください。", "answer": "～をみせてください。" },
    { "question": "well, then, in that case", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "じゃ" },
    { "question": "Give me ~, please.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～をください。" },
    { "question": "Italy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "イタリア" },
    { "question": "Switzerland", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スイス" },
    { "question": "France", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "フランス" },
    { "question": "Jakarta", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ジャカルタ" },
    { "question": "Bangkok", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "バンコク" },
    { "question": "Berlin", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ベルリン" }
  ],
  "N5L4VQuiz": [
    { "question": "get up, wake up", "kanji_question": "起きます", "answer": "おきます" },
    { "question": "sleep, go to bed", "kanji_question": "寝ます", "answer": "ねます" },
    { "question": "work", "kanji_question": "働きます", "answer": "はたらきます" },
    { "question": "take a rest, take a holiday", "kanji_question": "休みます", "answer": "やすみます" },
    { "question": "study", "kanji_question": "勉強します", "answer": "べんきょうします" },
    { "question": "finish", "kanji_question": "終わります", "answer": "おわります" },
    { "question": "department store", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "デパート" },
    { "question": "bank", "kanji_question": "銀行", "answer": "ぎんこう" },
    { "question": "post office", "kanji_question": "郵便局", "answer": "ゆうびんきょく" },
    { "question": "library", "kanji_question": "図書館", "answer": "としょかん" },
    { "question": "art museum", "kanji_question": "美術館", "answer": "びじゅつかん" },
    { "question": "now", "kanji_question": "今", "answer": "いま" },
    { "question": "~ o'clock", "kanji_question": "～時", "answer": "～じ" },
    { "question": "~ minute", "kanji_question": "～分", "answer": "～ふん（～ぷん）" },
    { "question": "half (30 minutes)", "kanji_question": "半", "answer": "はん" },
    { "question": "what time", "kanji_question": "何時", "answer": "なんじ" },
    { "question": "what minute", "kanji_question": "何分", "answer": "なんぷん" },
    { "question": "a.m., morning", "kanji_question": "午前", "answer": "ごぜん" },
    { "question": "p.m., afternoon", "kanji_question": "午後", "answer": "ごご" },
    { "question": "morning", "kanji_question": "朝", "answer": "あさ" },
    { "question": "daytime, noon", "kanji_question": "昼", "answer": "ひる" },
    { "question": "night, evening (1)", "kanji_question": "夜", "answer": "よる" },
    { "question": "night, evening (2)", "kanji_question": "晩", "answer": "ばん" },
    { "question": "the day before yesterday", "kanji_question": "一昨日", "answer": "おととい" },
    { "question": "yesterday", "kanji_question": "昨日", "answer": "きのう" },
    { "question": "today", "kanji_question": "今日", "answer": "きょう" },
    { "question": "tomorrow", "kanji_question": "明日", "answer": "あした" },
    { "question": "the day after tomorrow", "kanji_question": "明後日", "answer": "あさって" },
    { "question": "this morning", "kanji_question": "今朝", "answer": "けさ" },
    { "question": "this evening, tonight", "kanji_question": "今晩", "answer": "こんばん" },
    { "question": "rest, a holiday, a day off", "kanji_question": "休み", "answer": "やすみ" },
    { "question": "lunchtime", "kanji_question": "昼休み", "answer": "ひるやすみ" },
    { "question": "examination, test", "kanji_question": "試験", "answer": "しけん" },
    { "question": "meeting, conference", "kanji_question": "会議", "answer": "かいぎ" },
    { "question": "film, movie", "kanji_question": "映画", "answer": "えいが" },
    { "question": "every morning", "kanji_question": "毎朝", "answer": "まいあさ" },
    { "question": "every night", "kanji_question": "毎晩", "answer": "まいばん" },
    { "question": "every day", "kanji_question": "毎日", "answer": "まいにち" },
    { "question": "Monday", "kanji_question": "月曜日", "answer": "げつようび" },
    { "question": "Tuesday", "kanji_question": "火曜日", "answer": "かようび" },
    { "question": "Wednesday", "kanji_question": "水曜日", "answer": "すいようび" },
    { "question": "Thursday", "kanji_question": "木曜日", "answer": "もくようび" },
    { "question": "Friday", "kanji_question": "金曜日", "answer": "きんょうび" },
    { "question": "Saturday", "kanji_question": "土曜日", "answer": "どようび" },
    { "question": "Sunday", "kanji_question": "日曜日", "answer": "にちようび" },
    { "question": "what day of the week", "kanji_question": "何曜日", "answer": "なんょうび" },
    { "question": "from ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～から" },
    { "question": "up to ~, until ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～まで" },
    { "question": "and (noun + noun)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "と" },
    { "question": "That's tough, isn't it? (used when expressing sympathy)", "kanji_question": "大変ですね。", "answer": "たいへんですね。" },
    { "question": "number", "kanji_question": "番号", "answer": "ばんごう" },
    { "question": "what number", "kanji_question": "何番", "answer": "なんばん" },
    { "question": "your place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そちら" },
    { "question": "New York", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ニューヨーク" },
    { "question": "Beijing", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ペキン" },
    { "question": "Los Angeles", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ロサンゼルス" },
    { "question": "London", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ロンドン" }
  ],
  "N5L5VQuiz": [
    { "question": "go", "kanji_question": "行きます", "answer": "いきます" },
    { "question": "come", "kanji_question": "来ます", "answer": "きます" },
    { "question": "go home, return", "kanji_question": "帰ります", "answer": "かえります" },
    { "question": "school", "kanji_question": "学校", "answer": "がっこう" },
    { "question": "supermarket", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スーパー" },
    { "question": "station", "kanji_question": "駅", "answer": "えき" },
    { "question": "airplane", "kanji_question": "飛行機", "answer": "ひこうき" },
    { "question": "ship", "kanji_question": "船", "answer": "ふね" },
    { "question": "electric train", "kanji_question": "電車", "answer": "でんしゃ" },
    { "question": "subway, underground", "kanji_question": "地下鉄", "answer": "ちかてつ" },
    { "question": "the bullet train", "kanji_question": "新幹線", "answer": "しんかんせん" },
    { "question": "bus", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "バス" },
    { "question": "taxi", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "タクシー" },
    { "question": "bicycle", "kanji_question": "自転車", "answer": "じてんしゃ" },
    { "question": "on foot", "kanji_question": "歩いて", "answer": "あるいて" },
    { "question": "person, people", "kanji_question": "人", "answer": "ひと" },
    { "question": "friend", "kanji_question": "友達", "answer": "ともだち" },
    { "question": "he, boyfriend, lover", "kanji_question": "彼", "answer": "かれ" },
    { "question": "she, girlfriend, lover", "kanji_question": "彼女", "answer": "かのじょ" },
    { "question": "family", "kanji_question": "家族", "answer": "かぞく" },
    { "question": "alone, by oneself", "kanji_question": "一人で", "answer": "ひとりで" },
    { "question": "last week", "kanji_question": "先週", "answer": "せんしゅう" },
    { "question": "this week", "kanji_question": "今週", "answer": "こんしゅう" },
    { "question": "next week", "kanji_question": "来週", "answer": "らいしゅう" },
    { "question": "last month", "kanji_question": "先月", "answer": "せんげつ" },
    { "question": "this month", "kanji_question": "今月", "answer": "こんげつ" },
    { "question": "next month", "kanji_question": "来月", "answer": "らいげつ" },
    { "question": "last year", "kanji_question": "去年", "answer": "きょねん" },
    { "question": "this year", "kanji_question": "今年", "answer": "ことし" },
    { "question": "next year", "kanji_question": "来年", "answer": "らいねん" },
    { "question": "~th year", "kanji_question": "～年", "answer": "～ねん" },
    { "question": "what year", "kanji_question": "何年", "answer": "なんねん" },
    { "question": "~th month of the year", "kanji_question": "～月", "answer": "～がつ" },
    { "question": "what month", "kanji_question": "何月", "answer": "なんがつ" },
    { "question": "first day of the month", "kanji_question": "１日", "answer": "ついたち" },
    { "question": "second, two days", "kanji_question": "２日", "answer": "ふつか" },
    { "question": "third, three days", "kanji_question": "３日", "answer": "みっか" },
    { "question": "fourth, four days", "kanji_question": "４日", "answer": "よっか" },
    { "question": "fifth, five days", "kanji_question": "５日", "answer": "いつか" },
    { "question": "sixth, six days", "kanji_question": "６日", "answer": "むいか" },
    { "question": "seventh, seven days", "kanji_question": "７日", "answer": "なのか" },
    { "question": "eighth, eight days", "kanji_question": "８日", "answer": "ようか" },
    { "question": "ninth, nine days", "kanji_question": "９日", "answer": "ここのか" },
    { "question": "tenth, ten days", "kanji_question": "１０日", "answer": "とおか" },
    { "question": "fourteenth, fourteen days", "kanji_question": "１４日", "answer": "じゅうよっか" },
    { "question": "twentieth, twenty days", "kanji_question": "２０日", "answer": "はつか" },
    { "question": "twenty fourth, twenty four days", "kanji_question": "２４日", "answer": "にじゅうよっか" },
    { "question": "~th day of the month, ~ days", "kanji_question": "～日", "answer": "～にち" },
    { "question": "which day of the month, how many days", "kanji_question": "何日", "answer": "なんにち" },
    { "question": "when", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いつ" },
    { "question": "birthday", "kanji_question": "誕生日", "answer": "たんじょうび" },
    { "question": "Yes, it is.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そうですね。" },
    { "question": "Thank you very much.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「どうも」ありがとうございました。" },
    { "question": "You're welcome. Don't mention it.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どういたしまして。" },
    { "question": "platform ~, ~th platform", "kanji_question": "～番線", "answer": "～ばんせん" },
    { "question": "next", "kanji_question": "次の", "answer": "つぎの" },
    { "question": "local (train)", "kanji_question": "普通", "answer": "ふつう" },
    { "question": "rapid", "kanji_question": "急行", "answer": "きゅうこう" },
    { "question": "express", "kanji_question": "特急", "answer": "とっきゅう" }
  ],
  "N5L6VQuiz": [
    { "question": "eat", "kanji_question": "食べます", "answer": "たべます" },
    { "question": "drink", "kanji_question": "飲みます", "answer": "のみます" },
    { "question": "smoke (a cigarette)", "kanji_question": "吸います", "answer": "すいます" },
    { "question": "see, look at, watch", "kanji_question": "見ます", "answer": "みます" },
    { "question": "hear, listen", "kanji_question": "聞きます", "answer": "ききます" },
    { "question": "read", "kanji_question": "読みます", "answer": "よみます" },
    { "question": "write, draw, paint", "kanji_question": "書きます", "answer": "かきます" },
    { "question": "buy", "kanji_question": "買います", "answer": "かいます" },
    { "question": "take (a photograph)", "kanji_question": "撮ります", "answer": "とります" },
    { "question": "do", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "します" },
    { "question": "meet (a friend)", "kanji_question": "会います", "answer": "あいます" },
    { "question": "a meal, cooked rice", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ごはん" },
    { "question": "breakfast", "kanji_question": "朝ごはん", "answer": "あさごはん" },
    { "question": "lunch", "kanji_question": "昼ごはん", "answer": "ひるごはん" },
    { "question": "supper", "kanji_question": "晩ごはん", "answer": "ばんごはん" },
    { "question": "bread", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パン" },
    { "question": "egg", "kanji_question": "卵", "answer": "たまご" },
    { "question": "meat", "kanji_question": "肉", "answer": "にく" },
    { "question": "fish", "kanji_question": "魚", "answer": "さかな" },
    { "question": "vegetable", "kanji_question": "野菜", "answer": "やさい" },
    { "question": "fruit", "kanji_question": "果物", "answer": "くだもの" },
    { "question": "water", "kanji_question": "水", "answer": "みず" },
    { "question": "tea, green tea", "kanji_question": "お茶", "answer": "おちゃ" },
    { "question": "black tea", "kanji_question": "紅茶", "answer": "こうちゃ" },
    { "question": "milk", "kanji_question": "牛乳", "answer": "ぎゅうにゅう" },
    { "question": "juice", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ジュース" },
    { "question": "beer", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ビール" },
    { "question": "alcohol, Japanese rice wine", "kanji_question": "「お」酒", "answer": "「お」さけ" },
    { "question": "tobacco, cigarette", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たばこ" },
    { "question": "letter", "kanji_question": "手紙", "answer": "てがみ" },
    { "question": "report", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "レポート" },
    { "question": "photograph", "kanji_question": "写真", "answer": "しゃしｎ" },
    { "question": "video (tape), video deck", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ビデオ" },
    { "question": "shop, store", "kanji_question": "店", "answer": "みせ" },
    { "question": "garden", "kanji_question": "庭", "answer": "にわ" },
    { "question": "homework", "kanji_question": "宿題", "answer": "しゅくだい" },
    { "question": "tennis", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "テニス" },
    { "question": "soccer, football", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "サッカー" },
    { "question": "cherry-blossom viewing", "kanji_question": "「お」花見", "answer": "「お」はなみ" },
    { "question": "what", "kanji_question": "何", "answer": "なに" },
    { "question": "together", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いっしょに" },
    { "question": "a little while, a little bit", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ちょっと" },
    { "question": "always, usually", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いつも" },
    { "question": "sometimes", "kanji_question": "時々", "answer": "ときどき" },
    { "question": "after that, and then", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それから" },
    { "question": "yes", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ええ" },
    { "question": "That's good.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいですね。" },
    { "question": "I see.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "わかりました。" },
    { "question": "Yes? (lit: What is it?)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なんですか。" },
    { "question": "See you (tomorrow).", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "じゃ、また「あした」。" },
    { "question": "Mexico", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "メキシコ" }
  ],
  "N5L7VQuiz": [
    { "question": "cut, slice", "kanji_question": "切ります", "answer": "きります" },
    { "question": "send", "kanji_question": "送ります", "answer": "おくります" },
    { "question": "give", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あげます" },
    { "question": "receive", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もらいます" },
    { "question": "lend", "kanji_question": "貸します", "answer": "かします" },
    { "question": "borrow", "kanji_question": "借ります", "answer": "かります" },
    { "question": "teach", "kanji_question": "教えます", "answer": "おしえます" },
    { "question": "learn", "kanji_question": "習います", "answer": "ならいます" },
    { "question": "make (a telephone call)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かけます" },
    { "question": "hand, arm", "kanji_question": "手", "answer": "て" },
    { "question": "chopsticks", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はし" },
    { "question": "spoon", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スプーン" },
    { "question": "knife", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ナイフ" },
    { "question": "fork", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "フォーク" },
    { "question": "scissors", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はさみ" },
    { "question": "personal computer", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パソコン" },
    { "question": "mobile phone, cell phone", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ケータイ" },
    { "question": "e-mail", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "メール" },
    { "question": "New Year's greeting card", "kanji_question": "年賀状", "answer": "ねんがじょう" },
    { "question": "punch", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パンチ" },
    { "question": "stapler", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ホッチキス" },
    { "question": "Scotch tape, clear adhesive tape", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "セロテープ" },
    { "question": "eraser", "kanji_question": "消しゴム", "answer": "けしゴム" },
    { "question": "paper", "kanji_question": "紙", "answer": "かみ" },
    { "question": "flower, blossom", "kanji_question": "花", "answer": "はな" },
    { "question": "shirt", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シャツ" },
    { "question": "present, gift", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "プレゼント" },
    { "question": "baggage, parcel", "kanji_question": "荷物", "answer": "にもつ" },
    { "question": "money", "kanji_question": "お金", "answer": "おかね" },
    { "question": "ticket", "kanji_question": "切符", "answer": "きっぷ" },
    { "question": "Christmas", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "クリスマス" },
    { "question": "(my) father", "kanji_question": "父", "answer": "ちち" },
    { "question": "(my) mother", "kanji_question": "母", "answer": "はは" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) father", "kanji_question": "お父さん", "answer": "おとうさん" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) mother", "kanji_question": "お母さん", "answer": "おかあさん" },
    { "question": "already", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もう" },
    { "question": "not yet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まだ" },
    { "question": "from now on, soon", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これから" },
    { "question": "What a nice ~.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～はすてきですね。" },
    { "question": "How nice of you to come.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いらっしゃい。" },
    { "question": "Do come in.", "kanji_question": "どうぞお上がりください。", "answer": "どうぞおあがりください。" },
    { "question": "Thank you./May I?", "kanji_question": "失礼します。", "answer": "しつれいします。" },
    { "question": "Won't you have ~?/Would you like to have ~?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～はいかがですか。" },
    { "question": "Thank you./I accept.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いただきます。" },
    { "question": "That was delicious. (said after eating or drinking)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ごちそうさま「でした」。" },
    { "question": "Spain", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スペイン" }
  ],
  "N5L8VQuiz": [
    { "question": "handsome", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ハンサム" },
    { "question": "beautiful, clean", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "きれい" },
    { "question": "quiet", "kanji_question": "静か", "answer": "しずか" },
    { "question": "lively", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "にぎやか" },
    { "question": "famous", "kanji_question": "有名", "answer": "ゆうめい" },
    { "question": "kind", "kanji_question": "親切", "answer": "しんせつ" },
    { "question": "healthy, energetic, cheerful", "kanji_question": "元気", "answer": "げんき" },
    { "question": "free (time)", "kanji_question": "暇", "answer": "ひま" },
    { "question": "convenient", "kanji_question": "便利", "answer": "べんり" },
    { "question": "fine, nice, wonderful", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すてき" },
    { "question": "big, large", "kanji_question": "大きい", "answer": "おおきい" },
    { "question": "small, little", "kanji_question": "小さい", "answer": "ちいさい" },
    { "question": "new", "kanji_question": "新しい", "answer": "あたらしい" },
    { "question": "old (not of age)", "kanji_question": "古い", "answer": "ふるい" },
    { "question": "good", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いい" },
    { "question": "bad", "kanji_question": "悪い", "answer": "わるい" },
    { "question": "hot", "kanji_question": "暑い、熱い", "answer": "あつい" },
    { "question": "cold (temperature)", "kanji_question": "寒い", "answer": "さむい" },
    { "question": "cold (touch)", "kanji_question": "冷たい", "answer": "つめたい" },
    { "question": "difficult", "kanji_question": "難しい", "answer": "むずかしい" },
    { "question": "easy", "kanji_question": "易しい", "answer": "やさしい" },
    { "question": "expensive, tall, high", "kanji_question": "高い", "answer": "たかい" },
    { "question": "inexpensive", "kanji_question": "安い", "answer": "やすい" },
    { "question": "low", "kanji_question": "低い", "answer": "ひくい" },
    { "question": "interesting", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おもしろい" },
    { "question": "delicious, tasty", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おいしい" },
    { "question": "busy", "kanji_question": "忙しい", "answer": "いそがしい" },
    { "question": "enjoyable", "kanji_question": "楽しい", "answer": "たのしい" },
    { "question": "white", "kanji_question": "白い", "answer": "しろい" },
    { "question": "black", "kanji_question": "黒い", "answer": "くろい" },
    { "question": "red", "kanji_question": "赤い", "answer": "あかい" },
    { "question": "blue", "kanji_question": "青い", "answer": "あおい" },
    { "question": "cherry blossom", "kanji_question": "桜", "answer": "さくら" },
    { "question": "mountain", "kanji_question": "山", "answer": "やま" },
    { "question": "town, city", "kanji_question": "町", "answer": "まち" },
    { "question": "food", "kanji_question": "食べ物", "answer": "たべもの" },
    { "question": "place", "kanji_question": "所", "answer": "ところ" },
    { "question": "dormitory", "kanji_question": "寮", "answer": "りょう" },
    { "question": "restaurant", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "レストラン" },
    { "question": "life", "kanji_question": "生活", "answer": "せいかつ" },
    { "question": "work, business", "kanji_question": "「お」仕事", "answer": "「お」しごと" },
    { "question": "how", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どう" },
    { "question": "what kind of ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どんな～" },
    { "question": "very", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "とても" },
    { "question": "not so (used with negative)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あまり" },
    { "question": "and", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そして" },
    { "question": "~ but, ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～が、～" },
    { "question": "How are you?", "kanji_question": "お元気ですか。", "answer": "おげんきですか。" },
    { "question": "Well let me see.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そうですね。" },
    { "question": "Won't you have another cup of ~?", "kanji_question": "～、もう一杯いかがですか。", "answer": "～、もういっぱいいかがですか。" },
    { "question": "No, thank you.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいえ、けっこうです。" },
    { "question": "It's already ~ [, isn't it?].", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もう～です「ね」。" },
    { "question": "It's almost time to leave now.", "kanji_question": "そろそろ失礼します。", "answer": "そろそろしつれいします。" },
    { "question": "Not at all.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいえ。" },
    { "question": "Please come again.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "またいらっしゃってください。" },
    { "question": "Shanghai", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シャンハイ" },
    { "question": "the Golden Pavilion", "kanji_question": "金閣寺", "answer": "きんかくじ" },
    { "question": "Nara Park", "kanji_question": "奈良公園", "answer": "ならこうえん" },
    { "question": "Mt. Fuji", "kanji_question": "富士山", "answer": "ふじさん" }
  ],
  "N5L9VQuiz": [
    { "question": "understand", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "わかります" },
    { "question": "have", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あります" },
    { "question": "like", "kanji_question": "好き", "answer": "すき" },
    { "question": "dislike", "kanji_question": "嫌い", "answer": "きらい" },
    { "question": "good at", "kanji_question": "上手", "answer": "じょうず" },
    { "question": "poor at", "kanji_question": "下手", "answer": "へた" },
    { "question": "drinks", "kanji_question": "飲み物", "answer": "のみもの" },
    { "question": "dish (cooked food), cooking", "kanji_question": "料理", "answer": "りょうり" },
    { "question": "sport", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スポーツ" },
    { "question": "baseball", "kanji_question": "野球", "answer": "やきゅう" },
    { "question": "dance", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ダンス" },
    { "question": "trip, tour", "kanji_question": "旅行", "answer": "りょこう" },
    { "question": "music", "kanji_question": "音楽", "answer": "おんがく" },
    { "question": "song", "kanji_question": "歌", "answer": "うた" },
    { "question": "classical music", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "クラシック" },
    { "question": "jazz", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ジャズ" },
    { "question": "concert", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コンサート" },
    { "question": "karaoke", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カラオケ" },
    { "question": "traditional Japanese musical", "kanji_question": "歌舞伎", "answer": "かぶき" },
    { "question": "picture, drawing", "kanji_question": "絵", "answer": "え" },
    { "question": "letter, character", "kanji_question": "字", "answer": "じ" },
    { "question": "Chinese characters", "kanji_question": "漢字", "answer": "かんじ" },
    { "question": "Hiragana script", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ひらがな" },
    { "question": "Katakana script", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かたかな" },
    { "question": "the Roman alphabet", "kanji_question": "ローマ字", "answer": "ローマじ" },
    { "question": "small change", "kanji_question": "細かいお金", "answer": "こまかいおかね" },
    { "question": "ticket", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "チケット" },
    { "question": "time", "kanji_question": "時間", "answer": "じかん" },
    { "question": "something to do, errand", "kanji_question": "用事", "answer": "ようじ" },
    { "question": "appointment, promise", "kanji_question": "約束", "answer": "やくそく" },
    { "question": "side job, part-time", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アルバイト" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) husband", "kanji_question": "ご主人", "answer": "ごしゅじん" },
    { "question": "(my) husband", "kanji_question": "夫（主人）", "answer": "おっと（しゅじん）" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) wife", "kanji_question": "奥さん", "answer": "おくさん" },
    { "question": "(my) wife", "kanji_question": "妻（家内）", "answer": "つま（かない）" },
    { "question": "child", "kanji_question": "子ども", "answer": "こども" },
    { "question": "well, much", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "よく" },
    { "question": "mostly, roughly", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だいたい" },
    { "question": "many, much", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たくさん" },
    { "question": "a little, a few", "kanji_question": "少し", "answer": "すこし" },
    { "question": "not at all", "kanji_question": "全然", "answer": "ぜんぜん" },
    { "question": "early, quickly, fast", "kanji_question": "早く、速く", "answer": "はやく" },
    { "question": "because ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～から" },
    { "question": "why", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうして" },
    { "question": "Please lend it to me.", "kanji_question": "貸してください。", "answer": "かしてください。" },
    { "question": "Sure./Certainly.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいですよ。" },
    { "question": "I'm sorry but/Unfortunately", "kanji_question": "残念です「が」", "answer": "ざんねんです「が」" },
    { "question": "oh", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ああ" },
    { "question": "Won't you join me (us)?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いっしょにいかがですか。" },
    { "question": "~ is a bit difficult.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～はちょっと。" },
    { "question": "So you cannot?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だめですか。" },
    { "question": "Please ask me again some other time.", "kanji_question": "また今度お願いします。", "answer": "またこんどおねがいします。" }
  ],
  "N5L10VQuiz": [
    { "question": "exist, be (referring to inanimate things)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あります" },
    { "question": "exist, be (referring to animate things)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "います" },
    { "question": "various", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いろいろ" },
    { "question": "man", "kanji_question": "男の人", "answer": "おとこのひと" },
    { "question": "woman", "kanji_question": "女の人", "answer": "おんなのひと" },
    { "question": "boy", "kanji_question": "男の子", "answer": "おとこのこ" },
    { "question": "girl", "kanji_question": "女の子", "answer": "おんなのこ" },
    { "question": "dog", "kanji_question": "犬", "answer": "いぬ" },
    { "question": "cat", "kanji_question": "猫", "answer": "ねこ" },
    { "question": "panda", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パンダ" },
    { "question": "elephant", "kanji_question": "像", "answer": "ぞう" },
    { "question": "tree, wood", "kanji_question": "木", "answer": "き" },
    { "question": "thing", "kanji_question": "物", "answer": "もの" },
    { "question": "battery", "kanji_question": "電池", "answer": "でんち" },
    { "question": "box", "kanji_question": "箱", "answer": "はこ" },
    { "question": "switch", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スイッチ" },
    { "question": "refrigerator", "kanji_question": "冷蔵庫", "answer": "れいぞうこ" },
    { "question": "table", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "テーブル" },
    { "question": "bed", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ベッド" },
    { "question": "shelf", "kanji_question": "棚", "answer": "たな" },
    { "question": "door", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ドア" },
    { "question": "window", "kanji_question": "窓", "answer": "まど" },
    { "question": "mail box, postbox", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ポスト" },
    { "question": "building", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ビル" },
    { "question": "cash machine, ATM", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ATM" },
    { "question": "convenience store", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コンビニ" },
    { "question": "park", "kanji_question": "公園", "answer": "こうえん" },
    { "question": "coffee shop", "kanji_question": "喫茶店", "answer": "きっさてん" },
    { "question": "~ store", "kanji_question": "～屋", "answer": "～や" },
    { "question": "a fixed place to catch taxis, trains, etc.", "kanji_question": "乗り場", "answer": "のりば" },
    { "question": "perfecture", "kanji_question": "県", "answer": "けん" },
    { "question": "on, above, over", "kanji_question": "上", "answer": "うえ" },
    { "question": "under, below, beneath", "kanji_question": "下", "answer": "した" },
    { "question": "front, before", "kanji_question": "前", "answer": "まえ" },
    { "question": "back, behind", "kanji_question": "後ろ", "answer": "うしろ" },
    { "question": "right [side]", "kanji_question": "右", "answer": "みぎ" },
    { "question": "left [side]", "kanji_question": "左", "answer": "ひだり" },
    { "question": "in, inside", "kanji_question": "中", "answer": "なか" },
    { "question": "outside", "kanji_question": "外", "answer": "そと" },
    { "question": "next, next door", "kanji_question": "隣", "answer": "となり" },
    { "question": "near, vicinity", "kanji_question": "近く", "answer": "ちかく" },
    { "question": "between, among", "kanji_question": "間", "answer": "あいだ" },
    { "question": "~, ~, and so on", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～や～「など」" },
    { "question": "Thank you.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「どうも」すみません。" },
    { "question": "nam pla", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ナンプラー" },
    { "question": "corner, section", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こーなー" },
    { "question": "the most bottom", "kanji_question": "いちばん下", "answer": "いちばんした" }
  ],
  "N5L11VQuiz": [
    { "question": "have [a child]", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「こどもが」います" },
    { "question": "stay be [in Japan]", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「にほんに」います" },
    { "question": "take (time or money)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かかります" },
    { "question": "take a day off (work)", "kanji_question": "休みます", "answer": "やすみます" },
    { "question": "one", "kanji_question": "１つ", "answer": "ひとつ" },
    { "question": "two", "kanji_question": "２つ", "answer": "ふたつ" },
    { "question": "three", "kanji_question": "３つ", "answer": "みっつ" },
    { "question": "four", "kanji_question": "４つ", "answer": "よっつ" },
    { "question": "five", "kanji_question": "５つ", "answer": "いつつ" },
    { "question": "six", "kanji_question": "６つ", "answer": "むっつ" },
    { "question": "seven", "kanji_question": "７つ", "answer": "ななつ" },
    { "question": "eight", "kanji_question": "８つ", "answer": "やっつ" },
    { "question": "nine", "kanji_question": "９つ", "answer": "ここのつ" },
    { "question": "ten", "kanji_question": "１０", "answer": "とお" },
    { "question": "how many", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いくつ" },
    { "question": "one person", "kanji_question": "１人", "answer": "ひとり" },
    { "question": "two persons", "kanji_question": "２人", "answer": "ふたり" },
    { "question": "~ people", "kanji_question": "～人", "answer": "～にん" },
    { "question": "counter for machine, cars, etc.", "kanji_question": "～台", "answer": "～だい" },
    { "question": "counter for paper, stamps, etc.", "kanji_question": "～枚", "answer": "～まい" },
    { "question": "~ times", "kanji_question": "～回", "answer": "～かい" },
    { "question": "apple", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "りんご" },
    { "question": "mandarin orange", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "みかん" },
    { "question": "sandwich", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "サンドイッチ" },
    { "question": "curry [and rice]", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カレー「ライス」" },
    { "question": "ice cream", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アイスクリーム" },
    { "question": "stamp", "kanji_question": "切手", "answer": "きって" },
    { "question": "post card", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はがき" },
    { "question": "envelope", "kanji_question": "封筒", "answer": "ふうとう" },
    { "question": "parents", "kanji_question": "両親", "answer": "りょうしん" },
    { "question": "brothers and sisters", "kanji_question": "兄弟", "answer": "きょうだい" },
    { "question": "(my) elder brother", "kanji_question": "兄", "answer": "あに" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) elder brother", "kanji_question": "お兄さん", "answer": "おにいさん" },
    { "question": "(my) elder sister", "kanji_question": "姉", "answer": "あね" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) elder sister", "kanji_question": "お姉さん", "answer": "おねえさん" },
    { "question": "(my) younger brother", "kanji_question": "弟", "answer": "おとうと" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) younger brother", "kanji_question": "弟さん", "answer": "おとうとさん" },
    { "question": "(my) younger sister", "kanji_question": "妹", "answer": "いもうと" },
    { "question": "(someone else's) younger sister", "kanji_question": "妹さん", "answer": "いもうとさん" },
    { "question": "foreign country", "kanji_question": "外国", "answer": "がいこく" },
    { "question": "foreign student", "kanji_question": "留学生", "answer": "りゅうがくせい" },
    { "question": "class", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "クラス" },
    { "question": "~ hours", "kanji_question": "～時間", "answer": "～じかん" },
    { "question": "~ weeks", "kanji_question": "～週間", "answer": "～しゅうかん" },
    { "question": "~ months", "kanji_question": "～か月", "answer": "～かげつ" },
    { "question": "~ years", "kanji_question": "～年", "answer": "～ねん" },
    { "question": "about ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ぐらい" },
    { "question": "how long", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どのくらい" },
    { "question": "in total", "kanji_question": "全部で", "answer": "ぜんぶで" },
    { "question": "all, everything", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "みんな" },
    { "question": "only ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～だけ" },
    { "question": "Certainly, (Sir/Madam)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かしこまりました。" },
    { "question": "Nice weather, isn't it?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いい「お」てんきですね。" },
    { "question": "Are you going out?", "kanji_question": "お出かけですか。", "answer": "おでかけですか。" },
    { "question": "I'm just going to ~.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ちょっと～まで。" },
    { "question": "See you later./So long. (said by who is sending someone off)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いってらっしゃい。" },
    { "question": "See you later./So long. (said by who is going out)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いってきます。" },
    { "question": "see mail", "kanji_question": "船便", "answer": "ふなびん" },
    { "question": "airmail", "kanji_question": "航空便（エアメール）", "answer": "こうくうびん（エアメール）" },
    { "question": "Please. (lit. ask for a favour)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おねがいします。" },
    { "question": "Australia", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "オーストラリア" }
  ],
  "N5L12VQuiz": [
    { "question": "easy, simple", "kanji_question": "簡単", "answer": "かんたん" },
    { "question": "near", "kanji_question": "近い", "answer": "ちかい" },
    { "question": "far", "kanji_question": "遠い", "answer": "とおい" },
    { "question": "fast", "kanji_question": "速い", "answer": "はやい" },
    { "question": "early", "kanji_question": "早い", "answer": "はやい" },
    { "question": "slow, late", "kanji_question": "遅い", "answer": "おそい" },
    { "question": "many (people), much", "kanji_question": "多い", "answer": "おおい" },
    { "question": "few (people), a little", "kanji_question": "少ない", "answer": "すくない" },
    { "question": "warm", "kanji_question": "暖かい、温かい", "answer": "あたたかい" },
    { "question": "cool", "kanji_question": "涼しい", "answer": "すずしい" },
    { "question": "sweet", "kanji_question": "甘い", "answer": "あまい" },
    { "question": "hot, spicy", "kanji_question": "辛い", "answer": "からい" },
    { "question": "heavy", "kanji_question": "重い", "answer": "おもい" },
    { "question": "light", "kanji_question": "軽い", "answer": "かるい" },
    { "question": "prefer [coffee]", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「コーヒーが」いい" },
    { "question": "season", "kanji_question": "季節", "answer": "きせつ" },
    { "question": "spring", "kanji_question": "春", "answer": "はる" },
    { "question": "summer", "kanji_question": "夏", "answer": "なつ" },
    { "question": "autumn, fall", "kanji_question": "秋", "answer": "あき" },
    { "question": "winter", "kanji_question": "冬", "answer": "ふゆ" },
    { "question": "weather", "kanji_question": "天気", "answer": "てんき" },
    { "question": "rain, rainy", "kanji_question": "雨", "answer": "あめ" },
    { "question": "snow, snowy", "kanji_question": "雪", "answer": "ゆき" },
    { "question": "cloudy", "kanji_question": "曇り", "answer": "くもり" },
    { "question": "hotel", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ホテル" },
    { "question": "airport", "kanji_question": "空港", "answer": "くうこう" },
    { "question": "sea, ocean", "kanji_question": "海", "answer": "うみ" },
    { "question": "world", "kanji_question": "世界", "answer": "せかい" },
    { "question": "party", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パーティー" },
    { "question": "festival", "kanji_question": "「お」祭り", "answer": "「お」まつり" },
    { "question": "sukiyaki", "kanji_question": "すき焼き", "answer": "すきやき" },
    { "question": "sashimi", "kanji_question": "刺身", "answer": "さしみ" },
    { "question": "sushi", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「お」すし" },
    { "question": "tempura", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "てんぷら" },
    { "question": "pork", "kanji_question": "豚肉", "answer": "ぶたにく" },
    { "question": "chicken", "kanji_question": "とり肉", "answer": "とりにく" },
    { "question": "beef", "kanji_question": "牛肉", "answer": "ぎゅうにく" },
    { "question": "lemon", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "レモン" },
    { "question": "flower arrangement", "kanji_question": "生け花", "answer": "いけばな" },
    { "question": "maple, red leaves of autumn", "kanji_question": "紅葉", "answer": "もみじ" },
    { "question": "which one", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どちら" },
    { "question": "both", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どちらも" },
    { "question": "the most", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いちばん" },
    { "question": "by far", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ずっと" },
    { "question": "for the first time", "kanji_question": "初めて", "answer": "はじめて" },
    { "question": "I'm home.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ただいま。" },
    { "question": "Welcome home.", "kanji_question": "お帰りなさい。", "answer": "おかえりなさい。" },
    { "question": "Wow! Look at all those people!", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "わあ、すごいひとですね。" },
    { "question": "I'm tired.", "kanji_question": "疲れました。", "answer": "つかれました。" },
    { "question": "Hong Kong", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほんこん" },
    { "question": "Singapore", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シンガポール" }
  ],
  "N5L13VQuiz": [
    { "question": "enjoy oneself, play", "kanji_question": "遊びます", "answer": "あそびます" },
    { "question": "swim", "kanji_question": "泳ぎます", "answer": "およぎます" },
    { "question": "go to meet, welcome", "kanji_question": "迎えます", "answer": "むかえます" },
    { "question": "get tired", "kanji_question": "疲れます", "answer": "つかれます" },
    { "question": "get marry", "kanji_question": "結婚します", "answer": "けっこんします" },
    { "question": "do shopping", "kanji_question": "買い物します", "answer": "かいものします" },
    { "question": "have a meal, dine", "kanji_question": "食事します", "answer": "しょくじします" },
    { "question": "take a walk", "kanji_question": "散歩します", "answer": "さんぽします" },
    { "question": "hard, tough, severe, awful", "kanji_question": "大変", "answer": "たいへん" },
    { "question": "want (something)", "kanji_question": "欲しい", "answer": "ほしい" },
    { "question": "wide, spacious", "kanji_question": "広い", "answer": "ひろい" },
    { "question": "narrow, small", "kanji_question": "狭い", "answer": "せまい" },
    { "question": "swimming pool", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "プール" },
    { "question": "river", "kanji_question": "川", "answer": "かわ" },
    { "question": "fine arts", "kanji_question": "美術", "answer": "びじゅつ" },
    { "question": "fishing", "kanji_question": "釣り", "answer": "つり" },
    { "question": "skiing", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スキー" },
    { "question": "weekend", "kanji_question": "週末", "answer": "しゅうまつ" },
    { "question": "New Year's Day", "kanji_question": "「お」正月", "answer": "「お」しょうがつ" },
    { "question": "about (time)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ごろ" },
    { "question": "something", "kanji_question": "何か", "answer": "なにか" },
    { "question": "somewhere, some place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どこか" },
    { "question": "get thirsty", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "のどがかわきます。" },
    { "question": "get hungry", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おなかがすきます。" },
    { "question": "Let's do that.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そうしましょう。" },
    { "question": "May I take your order?", "kanji_question": "ご注文は？", "answer": "ごちゅうもんは？" },
    { "question": "set meal", "kanji_question": "定食", "answer": "ていしょく" },
    { "question": "bowl of rice topped with beef", "kanji_question": "牛どん", "answer": "ぎゅうどん" },
    { "question": "Please wait [a moment].", "kanji_question": "「少々」お待ちください。", "answer": "「しょうしょう」おまちください。" },
    { "question": "polite equivalent of です", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "でございます" },
    { "question": "separately", "kanji_question": "別々に", "answer": "べつべつに" }
  ],
  "N5L14VQuiz": [
    { "question": "turn on", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つけます" },
    { "question": "turn off", "kanji_question": "消します", "answer": "けします" },
    { "question": "open", "kanji_question": "開けます", "answer": "あけます" },
    { "question": "close, shut", "kanji_question": "閉めます", "answer": "しめます" },
    { "question": "hurry", "kanji_question": "急ぎます", "answer": "いそぎます" },
    { "question": "wait", "kanji_question": "待ちます", "answer": "まちます" },
    { "question": "hold", "kanji_question": "持ちます", "answer": "もちます" },
    { "question": "take, pass", "kanji_question": "取ります", "answer": "とります" },
    { "question": "help (with a task)", "kanji_question": "手伝います", "answer": "てつだいます" },
    { "question": "call", "kanji_question": "呼びます", "answer": "よびます" },
    { "question": "speak, talk", "kanji_question": "話します", "answer": "はなします" },
    { "question": "use", "kanji_question": "使います", "answer": "つかいます" },
    { "question": "stop, park", "kanji_question": "止めます", "answer": "とめます" },
    { "question": "show", "kanji_question": "見せます", "answer": "みせます" },
    { "question": "tell (an address)", "kanji_question": "教えます", "answer": "おしえます" },
    { "question": "sit down", "kanji_question": "座ります", "answer": "すわります" },
    { "question": "stand up", "kanji_question": "立ちます", "answer": "たちます" },
    { "question": "enter (a cafe)", "kanji_question": "入ります", "answer": "はいります" },
    { "question": "go out (of a cafe)", "kanji_question": "出ます", "answer": "でます" },
    { "question": "rain", "kanji_question": "降ります", "answer": "ふります" },
    { "question": "copy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コピーします" },
    { "question": "electricity, light", "kanji_question": "電気", "answer": "でんき" },
    { "question": "air conditioner", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "エアコン" },
    { "question": "passport", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パスポート" },
    { "question": "name", "kanji_question": "名前", "answer": "なまえ" },
    { "question": "address", "kanji_question": "住所", "answer": "じゅうしょ" },
    { "question": "map", "kanji_question": "地図", "answer": "ちず" },
    { "question": "salt", "kanji_question": "塩", "answer": "しお" },
    { "question": "sugar", "kanji_question": "砂糖", "answer": "さとう" },
    { "question": "question, problem, trouble", "kanji_question": "問題", "answer": "もんだい" },
    { "question": "answer", "kanji_question": "答え", "answer": "こたえ" },
    { "question": "how to read, way of reading", "kanji_question": "読み方", "answer": "よみかた" },
    { "question": "how to ~, way of ~ing", "kanji_question": "～方", "answer": "～かた" },
    { "question": "straight", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まっすぐ" },
    { "question": "slowly, leisurely", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ゆっくり" },
    { "question": "immediately", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すぐ" },
    { "question": "again", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "また" },
    { "question": "later", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あとで" },
    { "question": "a little more", "kanji_question": "もう少し", "answer": "もうすこし" },
    { "question": "~ more, another ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もう～" },
    { "question": "right (used when encouraging some course of action)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "さあ" },
    { "question": "Oh! (in surprising or in wonder)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あれ？" },
    { "question": "Turn to the right at the signal.", "kanji_question": "信号を右へ曲がってください。", "answer": "しんごうをみぎへまがってください。" },
    { "question": "I'd like to pay with this.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これでおねがいします。" },
    { "question": "change", "kanji_question": "お釣り", "answer": "おつり" }
  ],
  "N5L15VQuiz": [
    { "question": "put", "kanji_question": "置きます", "answer": "おきます" },
    { "question": "make, produce", "kanji_question": "作ります、造ります", "answer": "つくります" },
    { "question": "sell", "kanji_question": "売ります", "answer": "うります" },
    { "question": "get to know", "kanji_question": "知ります", "answer": "しります" },
    { "question": "be going to live", "kanji_question": "住みます", "answer": "すみます" },
    { "question": "do research", "kanji_question": "研究します", "answer": "けんきゅうします" },
    { "question": "materials, data", "kanji_question": "資料", "answer": "しりょう" },
    { "question": "catalog", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カタログ" },
    { "question": "timetable", "kanji_question": "時刻表", "answer": "じこくひょう" },
    { "question": "clothes", "kanji_question": "服", "answer": "ふく" },
    { "question": "products", "kanji_question": "製品", "answer": "せいひん" },
    { "question": "software", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ソフト" },
    { "question": "electronic dictionary", "kanji_question": "電子辞書", "answer": "でんしじしょ" },
    { "question": "economy", "kanji_question": "経済", "answer": "けいざい" },
    { "question": "municipal office, city hall", "kanji_question": "市役所", "answer": "しやくしょ" },
    { "question": "senior high school", "kanji_question": "高校", "answer": "こうこう" },
    { "question": "dentist", "kanji_question": "歯医者", "answer": "はいしゃ" },
    { "question": "single, unmarried", "kanji_question": "独身", "answer": "どくしん" },
    { "question": "I'm sorry.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すみません。" },
    { "question": "Ladies and Gentlemen, everybody", "kanji_question": "皆さん", "answer": "みなさん" },
    { "question": "remember, recollect", "kanji_question": "思い出します", "answer": "おもいだします" },
    { "question": "be (honorific equivalent of います)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いらっしゃいます。" }
  ],
  "N5L16VQuiz": [
    { "question": "ride, get on", "kanji_question": "乗ります", "answer": "のります" },
    { "question": "get off", "kanji_question": "降ります", "answer": "おります" },
    { "question": "change (trains, etc.)", "kanji_question": "乗り換えます", "answer": "のりかえます" },
    { "question": "take (a shower)", "kanji_question": "浴びます", "answer": "あびます" },
    { "question": "put in, insert", "kanji_question": "入れます", "answer": "いれます" },
    { "question": "take out, withdraw, submit", "kanji_question": "出します", "answer": "だします" },
    { "question": "withdraw", "kanji_question": "下ろします", "answer": "おろします" },
    { "question": "enter (university)", "kanji_question": "入ります", "answer": "はいります" },
    { "question": "graduate from (university)", "kanji_question": "出ます", "answer": "でます" },
    { "question": "press, push", "kanji_question": "押します", "answer": "おします" },
    { "question": "drink alcohol", "kanji_question": "飲みます", "answer": "のみます" },
    { "question": "start, begin", "kanji_question": "始めます", "answer": "はじめます" },
    { "question": "tour, visit a place to study it", "kanji_question": "見学します", "answer": "けんがくします" },
    { "question": "phone", "kanji_question": "電話します", "answer": "でんわします" },
    { "question": "young", "kanji_question": "若い", "answer": "わかい" },
    { "question": "long", "kanji_question": "長い", "answer": "ながい" },
    { "question": "short", "kanji_question": "短い", "answer": "みじかい" },
    { "question": "bright, light", "kanji_question": "明るい", "answer": "あかるい" },
    { "question": "dark", "kanji_question": "暗い", "answer": "くらい" },
    { "question": "body", "kanji_question": "体", "answer": "からだ" },
    { "question": "head", "kanji_question": "頭", "answer": "あたま" },
    { "question": "hair", "kanji_question": "髪", "answer": "かみ" },
    { "question": "face", "kanji_question": "顔", "answer": "かお" },
    { "question": "eye", "kanji_question": "目", "answer": "め" },
    { "question": "ear", "kanji_question": "耳", "answer": "みみ" },
    { "question": "nose", "kanji_question": "鼻", "answer": "はな" },
    { "question": "mouth", "kanji_question": "口", "answer": "くち" },
    { "question": "teeth", "kanji_question": "歯", "answer": "は" },
    { "question": "stomach", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おなか" },
    { "question": "leg, foot", "kanji_question": "足", "answer": "あし" },
    { "question": "height", "kanji_question": "背", "answer": "せ" },
    { "question": "service", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "サービス" },
    { "question": "jogging", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ジョギング" },
    { "question": "shower", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シャワー" },
    { "question": "green, greenery", "kanji_question": "緑", "answer": "みどり" },
    { "question": "Buddhist temple", "kanji_question": "「お」寺", "answer": "「お」てら" },
    { "question": "Shinto shrine", "kanji_question": "神社", "answer": "じんじゃ" },
    { "question": "number ~", "kanji_question": "～番", "answer": "～ばん" },
    { "question": "in what way, how", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうやって" },
    { "question": "which ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どの～" },
    { "question": "which one (of three or more things)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どれ" },
    { "question": "That's amazing!", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すごいですね。" },
    { "question": "[No,] I still have a long way to go.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「いいえ、」まだまだです。" },
    { "question": "Are you making a withdrawal?", "kanji_question": "お引き出しですか。", "answer": "おひきだしですか。" },
    { "question": "first of all", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まず" },
    { "question": "next, as a next step", "kanji_question": "次に", "answer": "つぎに" },
    { "question": "cash dispensing card", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "キャッシュカード" },
    { "question": "personal identification number, PIN", "kanji_question": "暗証番号", "answer": "あんしょうばんごう" },
    { "question": "amount of money", "kanji_question": "金額", "answer": "きんがく" },
    { "question": "confirmation", "kanji_question": "確認", "answer": "かくにん" },
    { "question": "button", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ボタン" },
    { "question": "Japan Railway", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "JR" },
    { "question": "Snow Festival", "kanji_question": "雪祭り", "answer": "ゆきまつり" }
  ],
  "N5L17VQuiz": [
    { "question": "memorize", "kanji_question": "覚えます", "answer": "おぼえます" },
    { "question": "forget", "kanji_question": "忘れます", "answer": "わすれます" },
    { "question": "lose", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なくします" },
    { "question": "pay", "kanji_question": "払います", "answer": "はらいます" },
    { "question": "give back, return", "kanji_question": "返します", "answer": "かえします" },
    { "question": "go out", "kanji_question": "出かけます", "answer": "でかけます" },
    { "question": "take off (clothes, shoes, etc.)", "kanji_question": "脱ぎます", "answer": "ぬぎます" },
    { "question": "take (something)", "kanji_question": "持って行きます", "answer": "もっていきます" },
    { "question": "bring (something)", "kanji_question": "持って来ます", "answer": "もってきます" },
    { "question": "worry", "kanji_question": "心配します", "answer": "しんぱいします" },
    { "question": "work overtime", "kanji_question": "残業します", "answer": "ざんぎょうします" },
    { "question": "go on business trip", "kanji_question": "出張します", "answer": "しゅっちょうします" },
    { "question": "take (medicine)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "のみます" },
    { "question": "take (a bath)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はいります" },
    { "question": "important, precious", "kanji_question": "大切", "answer": "たいせつ" },
    { "question": "all right", "kanji_question": "大丈夫", "answer": "だいじょうぶ" },
    { "question": "dangerous", "kanji_question": "危ない", "answer": "あぶない" },
    { "question": "no smoking", "kanji_question": "禁煙", "answer": "きんえん" },
    { "question": "[health] insurance card", "kanji_question": "「健康」保険証", "answer": "「けんこう」ほけんしょう" },
    { "question": "fever", "kanji_question": "熱", "answer": "ねつ" },
    { "question": "illness", "kanji_question": "病気", "answer": "びょうき" },
    { "question": "medicine", "kanji_question": "薬", "answer": "くすり" },
    { "question": "bath", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「お」ふろ" },
    { "question": "jacket, outerwear", "kanji_question": "上着", "answer": "うわぎ" },
    { "question": "underwear", "kanji_question": "下着", "answer": "したぎ" },
    { "question": "two or three days", "kanji_question": "２，３日", "answer": "２，３にち" },
    { "question": "two or three ~ (where ~ is a counter suffix)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "２，３～" },
    { "question": "before ~, by ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～までに" },
    { "question": "therefore, so", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ですから" },
    { "question": "What's the matter?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうしましたか。" },
    { "question": "throat", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "のど" },
    { "question": "I have a pain [in my ~]", "kanji_question": "「～が」痛いです。", "answer": "「～が」いたいです。" },
    { "question": "cold, flu", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かぜ" },
    { "question": "and, furthermore", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "" },
    { "question": "Take care of yourself.", "kanji_question": "お大事に。", "answer": "おだいじに。" }
  ],
  "N5L18VQuiz": [
    { "question": "be able to, can", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "できます" },
    { "question": "wash", "kanji_question": "洗います", "answer": "あらいます" },
    { "question": "play (stringed instrument or piano, etc)", "kanji_question": "弾きます", "answer": "ひきます" },
    { "question": "sing", "kanji_question": "歌います", "answer": "うたいます" },
    { "question": "collect, gather", "kanji_question": "集めます", "answer": "あつめます" },
    { "question": "throw away", "kanji_question": "捨てます", "answer": "すてます" },
    { "question": "exchange, change", "kanji_question": "換えます", "answer": "かえます" },
    { "question": "drive", "kanji_question": "運転します", "answer": "うんてんします" },
    { "question": "reserve, book", "kanji_question": "予約します", "answer": "よやくします" },
    { "question": "piano", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ピアノ" },
    { "question": "~ meter", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～メートル" },
    { "question": "cash", "kanji_question": "現金", "answer": "げんきん" },
    { "question": "hobby", "kanji_question": "趣味", "answer": "しゅみ" },
    { "question": "diary", "kanji_question": "日記", "answer": "にっき" },
    { "question": "prayer", "kanji_question": "「お」祈り", "answer": "「お」いのり" },
    { "question": "section chief", "kanji_question": "課長", "answer": "かちょう" },
    { "question": "department chief", "kanji_question": "部長", "answer": "ぶちょう" },
    { "question": "company president", "kanji_question": "社長", "answer": "しゃちょう" },
    { "question": "animal", "kanji_question": "動物", "answer": "どうぶつ" },
    { "question": "horse", "kanji_question": "馬", "answer": "うま" },
    { "question": "the internet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "インターネット" },
    { "question": "especially", "kanji_question": "特に", "answer": "とくに" },
    { "question": "Really! (used when expressing surpirse)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "へえ" },
    { "question": "That interesting, isn't it?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それはおもしろいですね。" },
    { "question": "not easily (used with negative)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なかなか" },
    { "question": "Really?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほんとうですか。" },
    { "question": "by all means, really", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ぜひ" },
    { "question": "song title meaning 'Home Town'", "kanji_question": "故郷", "answer": "ふるさと" },
    { "question": "the Beatles", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ビートルズ" }
  ],
  "N5L19VQuiz": [
    { "question": "climb (a mountain)", "kanji_question": "登ります、上ります", "answer": "のぼります" },
    { "question": "stay (at a hotel)", "kanji_question": "泊まります", "answer": "とまります" },
    { "question": "clean (a room)", "kanji_question": "掃除します", "answer": "そうじします" },
    { "question": "wash (clothes)", "kanji_question": "洗濯します", "answer": "せんたくします" },
    { "question": "become", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なります" },
    { "question": "sleepy", "kanji_question": "眠い", "answer": "ねむい" },
    { "question": "strong", "kanji_question": "強い", "answer": "つよい" },
    { "question": "weak", "kanji_question": "弱い", "answer": "よわい" },
    { "question": "practice", "kanji_question": "練習", "answer": "れんしゅう" },
    { "question": "golf", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ゴルフ" },
    { "question": "sumo wrestling", "kanji_question": "相撲", "answer": "すもう" },
    { "question": "tea ceremony", "kanji_question": "お茶", "answer": "おちゃ" },
    { "question": "day, date", "kanji_question": "日", "answer": "ひ" },
    { "question": "condition", "kanji_question": "調子", "answer": "ちょうし" },
    { "question": "once", "kanji_question": "一度", "answer": "いちど" },
    { "question": "not once, never", "kanji_question": "一度も", "answer": "いちども" },
    { "question": "gradually", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だんだん" },
    { "question": "soon", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もうすぐ" },
    { "question": "Thank you.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おかげさまで。" },
    { "question": "but", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "でも" },
    { "question": "Bottoms up./Cheers!", "kanji_question": "乾杯", "answer": "かんぱい" },
    { "question": "diet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ダイエット" },
    { "question": "excessive, impossible", "kanji_question": "無理", "answer": "むり" },
    { "question": "good for one's health", "kanji_question": "体にいい", "answer": "からだにいい" }
  ],
  "N5L20VQuiz": [
    { "question": "need, require (a visa)", "kanji_question": "要ります", "answer": "いります" },
    { "question": "check, investigate", "kanji_question": "調べます", "answer": "しらべます" },
    { "question": "repair", "kanji_question": "修理します", "answer": "しゅうりします" },
    { "question": "I", "kanji_question": "僕", "answer": "ぼく" },
    { "question": "you", "kanji_question": "君", "answer": "きみ" },
    { "question": "Mr. (an informal equivalent of ～さん used to address people of equal or lower status)", "kanji_question": "～君", "answer": "～くん" },
    { "question": "yes (an informal equivalent of はい)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うん" },
    { "question": "no (an informal equivalent of いいえ)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ううん" },
    { "question": "word", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ことば" },
    { "question": "kimono", "kanji_question": "着物", "answer": "きもの" },
    { "question": "visa", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ビザ" },
    { "question": "the beginning", "kanji_question": "初め", "answer": "はじめ" },
    { "question": "the end", "kanji_question": "終わり", "answer": "おわり" },
    { "question": "this way, this place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こっち" },
    { "question": "this way, that place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そっち" },
    { "question": "this way, that place over there", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あっち" },
    { "question": "which one, which way, where", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どっち" },
    { "question": "all together", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "みんなで" },
    { "question": "~ but", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～けど" },
    { "question": "I'm full.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おなかがいっぱいです。" },
    { "question": "if you like", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "よかったら" },
    { "question": "various", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いろいろ" }
  ],
  "N5L21VQuiz": [
    { "question": "think", "kanji_question": "思います", "answer": "おもいます" },
    { "question": "say", "kanji_question": "言います", "answer": "いいます" },
    { "question": "win", "kanji_question": "勝ちます", "answer": "かちます" },
    { "question": "lose", "kanji_question": "負けます", "answer": "まけます" },
    { "question": "[a festival] be held, take place", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「おまつりが～」あります" },
    { "question": "be useful", "kanji_question": "役に立ちます", "answer": "やくにたちます" },
    { "question": "move, work", "kanji_question": "動きます", "answer": "うごきます" },
    { "question": "quit or retire from, stop, give up", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やめます" },
    { "question": "pay attention, take care", "kanji_question": "気をつけます", "answer": "きをつけます" },
    { "question": "study abroad", "kanji_question": "留学します", "answer": "りゅうがくします" },
    { "question": "wasteful", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "むだ" },
    { "question": "inconvenient", "kanji_question": "不便", "answer": "ふべん" },
    { "question": "awful, great", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すごい" },
    { "question": "TRUE", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほんとう" },
    { "question": "lie", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うそ" },
    { "question": "car, automobile", "kanji_question": "自動車", "answer": "じどうしゃ" },
    { "question": "transport, traffic", "kanji_question": "交通", "answer": "こうつう" },
    { "question": "(commodity) prices", "kanji_question": "物価", "answer": "ぶっか" },
    { "question": "announcement, broadcast", "kanji_question": "放送", "answer": "ほうそう" },
    { "question": "news", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ニュース" },
    { "question": "Japanese animated film", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アニメ" },
    { "question": "comic book", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "マンガ" },
    { "question": "design", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "デザイン" },
    { "question": "dream", "kanji_question": "夢", "answer": "ゆめ" },
    { "question": "genius", "kanji_question": "天才", "answer": "てんさい" },
    { "question": "game, match", "kanji_question": "試合", "answer": "しあい" },
    { "question": "opinion", "kanji_question": "意見", "answer": "いけん" },
    { "question": "talk, speech, what, one says, story", "kanji_question": "話", "answer": "はなし" },
    { "question": "earth", "kanji_question": "地球", "answer": "ちきゅう" },
    { "question": "moon", "kanji_question": "月", "answer": "つき" },
    { "question": "recently, these days", "kanji_question": "最近", "answer": "さいきん" },
    { "question": "probably, perhaps, maybe", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たぶん" },
    { "question": "surely", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "きっと" },
    { "question": "really", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほんとうに" },
    { "question": "not so much", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そんなに" },
    { "question": "about ~, concerning ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～について" },
    { "question": "It's been a long time since we last met.", "kanji_question": "久しぶりですね。", "answer": "ひさしぶりですね。" },
    { "question": "How about drinking ~ or something?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～でものみませんか。" },
    { "question": "of course", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もちろん" },
    { "question": "I have to get home now.", "kanji_question": "もう帰らないと。", "answer": "もうかえらないと。" },
    { "question": "heroine of the old Japanese folk tale 'Taketori Monogatari'", "kanji_question": "かぐや姫", "answer": "かぐやひめ" },
    { "question": "kangaroo", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カンガルー" }
  ],
  "N5L22VQuiz": [
    { "question": "put on (a shirt, etc.)", "kanji_question": "着ます", "answer": "きます" },
    { "question": "put on (shoes, trousers, etc.)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はきます" },
    { "question": "put on (a hat, etc.)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かぶります" },
    { "question": "put on (glasses)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かけます" },
    { "question": "put on (tie)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "します" },
    { "question": "be born", "kanji_question": "生まれます", "answer": "うまれます" },
    { "question": "we", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "わたしたち" },
    { "question": "coat", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コート" },
    { "question": "sweater", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "セーター" },
    { "question": "suit", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スーツ" },
    { "question": "hat, cap", "kanji_question": "帽子", "answer": "ぼうし" },
    { "question": "glasses", "kanji_question": "眼鏡", "answer": "めがね" },
    { "question": "cake", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ケーキ" },
    { "question": "box lunch", "kanji_question": "「お」弁当", "answer": "「お」べんとう" },
    { "question": "robot", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ロボット" },
    { "question": "humor", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ユーモア" },
    { "question": "convenience", "kanji_question": "都合", "answer": "つごう" },
    { "question": "often", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "よく" },
    { "question": "well, let me see", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "えーと" },
    { "question": "Congratulations. (used on birthdays, at weddings, New Year's Day, etc.)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おめでとう「ございます」。" },
    { "question": "Are you looking for ~?", "kanji_question": "お探しですか。", "answer": "おさがしですか。" },
    { "question": "Well then,", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "では" },
    { "question": "this (polite equivalent of これ)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こちら" },
    { "question": "rent", "kanji_question": "家賃", "answer": "やちん" },
    { "question": "kitchen with dining area", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ダイニングキッチン" },
    { "question": "Japanese-style room", "kanji_question": "和室", "answer": "わしつ" },
    { "question": "Japanese-style closet", "kanji_question": "押し入れ", "answer": "おしいれ" },
    { "question": "Japanese-style mattress and quilt", "kanji_question": "布団", "answer": "ふとん" },
    { "question": "Paris", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パリ" }
  ],
  "N5L23VQuiz": [
    { "question": "ask (the teacher)", "kanji_question": "聞きます", "answer": "ききます" },
    { "question": "turn", "kanji_question": "回します", "answer": "まわします" },
    { "question": "pull", "kanji_question": "引きます", "answer": "ひきます" },
    { "question": "change", "kanji_question": "変えます", "answer": "かえます" },
    { "question": "touch (a door)", "kanji_question": "触ります", "answer": "さわります" },
    { "question": "(change) come out", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "でます" },
    { "question": "walk (along a road)", "kanji_question": "歩きます", "answer": "あるきます" },
    { "question": "cross (a bridge)", "kanji_question": "渡ります", "answer": "わたります" },
    { "question": "turn (to the right)", "kanji_question": "曲がります", "answer": "まがります" },
    { "question": "lonely", "kanji_question": "寂しい", "answer": "さびしい" },
    { "question": "hot water", "kanji_question": "「お」湯", "answer": "「お」ゆ" },
    { "question": "sound", "kanji_question": "音", "answer": "おと" },
    { "question": "size", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "サイズ" },
    { "question": "breakdown", "kanji_question": "故障", "answer": "こしょう" },
    { "question": "road, way", "kanji_question": "道", "answer": "みち" },
    { "question": "crossroad", "kanji_question": "交差点", "answer": "こうさてん" },
    { "question": "traffic light", "kanji_question": "信号", "answer": "しんごう" },
    { "question": "corner", "kanji_question": "角", "answer": "かど" },
    { "question": "bridge", "kanji_question": "橋", "answer": "はし" },
    { "question": "parking lot, car park", "kanji_question": "駐車場", "answer": "ちゅうしゃじょう" },
    { "question": "building", "kanji_question": "建物", "answer": "たてもの" },
    { "question": "many times", "kanji_question": "何回も", "answer": "なんかいも" },
    { "question": "the ~th", "kanji_question": "～目", "answer": "～め" }
  ],
  "N5L24VQuiz": [
    { "question": "give (me)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "くれます" },
    { "question": "repair, correct", "kanji_question": "直します", "answer": "なおします" },
    { "question": "take (someone)", "kanji_question": "連れて行きます", "answer": "つれていきます" },
    { "question": "bring (someone)", "kanji_question": "連れて来ます", "answer": "つれてきます" },
    { "question": "escort (someone), go with", "kanji_question": "送ります", "answer": "おくります" },
    { "question": "introduce", "kanji_question": "紹介します", "answer": "しょうかいします" },
    { "question": "show around, show the way", "kanji_question": "案内します", "answer": "あんないします" },
    { "question": "explain", "kanji_question": "説明します", "answer": "せつめいします" },
    { "question": "grandfather, old man (1)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おじいさん" },
    { "question": "grandfather, old man (2)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おじいちゃん" },
    { "question": "grandmother, old woman (1)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おばあさん" },
    { "question": "grandmother, old woman (2)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おばあちゃん" },
    { "question": "preparation", "kanji_question": "準備", "answer": "じゅんび" },
    { "question": "moving out", "kanji_question": "引っ越し", "answer": "ひっこし" },
    { "question": "sweets, snacks", "kanji_question": "「お」菓子", "answer": "「お」かし" },
    { "question": "homestay", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ホームステイ" },
    { "question": "all", "kanji_question": "全部", "answer": "ぜんぶ" },
    { "question": "by oneself", "kanji_question": "自分で", "answer": "じぶんで" },
    { "question": "besides", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほかに" },
    { "question": "Mother's Day", "kanji_question": "母の日", "answer": "ははのひ" }
  ],
  "N5L25VQuiz": [
    { "question": "think, consider", "kanji_question": "考えます", "answer": "かんがえます" },
    { "question": "arrive (at the station)", "kanji_question": "着きます", "answer": "つきます" },
    { "question": "grow old", "kanji_question": "取ります", "answer": "とります" },
    { "question": "be enough, be sufficient", "kanji_question": "足ります", "answer": "たります" },
    { "question": "hometown", "kanji_question": "田舎", "answer": "いなか" },
    { "question": "chance", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "チャンス" },
    { "question": "hundred million", "kanji_question": "憶", "answer": "おく" },
    { "question": "if~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もし「～たら」" },
    { "question": "meaning", "kanji_question": "意味", "answer": "いみ" },
    { "question": "hello (used on the phone)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もしもし" },
    { "question": "transfer", "kanji_question": "転勤", "answer": "てんきん" },
    { "question": "thing, matter", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こと" },
    { "question": "free time", "kanji_question": "暇", "answer": "ひま" },
    { "question": "Thank you for everything you've done for me.", "kanji_question": "「いろいろ」お世話になりました。", "answer": "「いろいろ」おせわになりました。" },
    { "question": "do one's best", "kanji_question": "頑張ります", "answer": "がんばります" },
    { "question": "Best of luck.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうぞおげんきで。" },
    { "question": "Vietnam", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ベトナム" }
  ]
}
